# AMAR MOHAMMED

Swindon · 07763585365

<u>Am.inspiredsolutions@gmail.com</u> · LinkedIn Profile · <a href="https://uk.linkedin.com/in/amar-mohammed-4a185b55">https://uk.linkedin.com/in/amar-mohammed-4a185b55</a>

Experienced developer with proven track in delivering in tight timescales with the ability to communicate with people at different levels of the organization.

Over the last three-year period, I have developed software skills that have enabled me to further progress in my career. In addition to deploying and configuring advanced managed systems, I have developed skills in software coding languages such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Ajax, Angular along with some others. I have experience in systems like Jira, Git and Github, allowing me to work in a collaborative teams, both large and small, while keeping my code in line with version control. I have also worked with APIs both pushing and pulling information in a secure and stable manner. Node JS and TypeScript are recent skills, which I have developed thus further enhancing my JavaScript. My development was done through both projects and academia, using platforms such as code academy, Tree house academy and W3schools.

Coding for many years, I have a great understanding of text editors such as Visual Studio, enabling me to work efficiently and accurately through any task. From working on a wide variety of projects, I understand the foundation of web, from hosting and DNS through to website creation and web app development, deployment and support.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# JUNE 2016 – PRESENT CONSULTANT, SEISMI

Initially a consultant implementing solutions for large corporate clients such as Virgin Money and Rolls-Royce. My role entailed implementing complex solutions such as Oracle Data Relationship Management to produce the standardized reports for Financial Directors or those of similar roles. Using Data and Master data management and governance/workflows, I learnt to manage master data in a central location with the necessary business rules/validations applied. Using custom JavaScript code, I created and maintained sophisticated properties against the master data, enriching the data for downstream and upstream systems. Eventually changing the standardized approach to this Oracle product through coding enhancements, customizing the product/solution to exceed the client expectations.

I than moved onto using Ajax, APIs, Nodejs and angular to assist in building an in-house web application tool, later to be sold. Through this project I used git and git hub for version control for any code I published while working in a management software called Jira. Working in both development and support, I gained a breath of experience on a web application from the cradle to the grave.

JANUARY 2014 – JUNE 2016
THIRDLINE, PROJECT MANAGER

While working at enviz I was appointed a project manager at the partner company Thirdline. This promotion was due mainly to my development in task management and customer relationship building.

This role involved me gathering and documenting business and functional requirements to a high standard for bespoke software construction projects. I also worked closely with business focal points, Project Managers, and Application Team Leads to ensure successful project delivery. My role meant I worked with solution architects and technical leads to ensure that the designs take full account of specific requirements and constraints.

#### **JUNE 2012 - JANUARY 2014**

## **SENIOR SOLUTIONS SPECALIST, ENVIZ IT**

enviz IT are certified IT Support Specialists based in Swindon, providing bespoke IT support for SMEs. Part of the larger enviz group working with Communications and IT Support to Network Penetration and Cloud Based Solutions. Working in a team of 20, the role of Senior Solutions Specialist includes: Server, Network and Wireless installations; cloud infrastructure migrations, maintenance and troubleshooting; virtual migrations for VMWare, Citrix Xen Desktop, Xen Desktop and Hyper-V systems; Telecommunications; construction of Cloud-based infrastructure including Data Centers and hardware; Cyber-security.

# **EDUCATION**

**JUNE 2012** 

# BSC BUSINESS INFORMATION SYSTEMS DEGREE, UNIVERSITY OF

#### **GLOUCESTERSHIRE**

Final Grade 2:1 - This degree combined the best parts of business and computing degrees. By the time I graduated, I understood what makes the business world tick and how information systems are integral to business growth in the 21st century.

## SKILLS

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- jQuery
- SQL
- Ajax
- Nodeis
- Git and Git Hub
- Angular
- DNS
- Microsoft Office 365 and Azure
- Amazon AWS

- Software testing and debugging
- Problem Solving and Critical Thinking
- Collaboration Team Player
- Ability to adapt quickly
- Windows machine and software specialist
- Windows and Apple OS experienced
- Virtual machine setup and maintenance
- ISO 9001 and ISO 27001
- Ability to lead when necessary and follow when necessary

# **ACTIVITIES**

I am a young driven individual that has a real passion for anything IT. While on my journey I have become a loving father and trying husband and a car fanatic, all while trying to find the time to fit the weekly 5 a side football game in.